Contact

9028608108 (Mobile) shumeelansar.m@somaiya.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/shumeel-momin-450295116 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Research and Development (R&D)
Medical Device R&D
Product Design

Languages

English (Full Professional) Hindi (Native or Bilingual) Urdu (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Participated in the 13th International conference on Advanced Technologies & Treatments for Diabetes (ATTD 2020) held at Madrid, Spain.

Qualified GATE 2014 with score 471 & 93.78 percentile in Mechanical Engineering.

Participated and volunteered at TechConnect 2020 held at IIT Bombay, Powai.

Participated in the "Venture base camp on Clinical Study for Medical Devices and In Vitro Diagnostics" held at Venture Center. Pune.

Winner of "Hydrodatam" organised by "Converges 2013" 4th National level inter-challenge symposiums at RCPIT, Shirpur (National Level).

Publications

Design and Fabrication of Abrasive Jet Machine for Machining Glass Using Sea Sand.

Shumeel Momin

Lead Engineer R&D at Ayati Devices Pvt Ltd, IIT Bombay | Medical Device | Research and Development (R&D) | Product Design & Development

Thane

Summary

Experienced Lead Engineer in R&D with a demonstrated history of working in the Healthcare (Medical Devices) as well as manufacturing industry. Skilled in AutoCAD Mechanical, Solidworks, Fusion 360, PTC Creo, Ansys & other cad cam softwares. Strong research professional with a Master of Technology - MTech specialised in Cad/Cam & Robotics from K J Somaiya COE, Mumbai.

Experience

Ayati Devices Pvt Ltd, IIT Bombay Lead Engineer R&D June 2019 - Present (2 years 10 months) Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

Bhaviplast Private Limited Senior QA/QC Engineer July 2018 - June 2019 (1 year) Thane, Maharashtra, India

Metaform Enterprise
Design & Quality engineer
July 2014 - July 2015 (1 year 1 month)
India

Education

KJ Somaiya College of Engineering, Vidyavihar

Master of Technology - MTech, Mechanical Engineering (2015 - 2017)

Jamia Islamia Ishaatul Ulooms Jamia Institute of Engineering and Management Studies, Akkalkuwa

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Mechanical Engineering · (2011 - 2014)

ANJUMAN-I-ISLAMS SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY ATANJUMAN-I-ISLAM KALSEKAR TECHNICAL, MUMBAI

Diploma, Mechanical Engineering · (2008 - 2011)